AUSTIN J. SIMPKINS

DIGITAL DESIGNER / DEVELOPER / MARKETING SPECIALIST

A digital designer, developer, and marketing specialist based in Long Beach, California helping companies with achieving high converting websites and exceptional digital marketing strategy. Key skills include: website development, branding, ux/ui, drone photography, digital marketing services (marketing automation systems, lead nurturing, content marketing, email marketing, social media). Experience with working in a collaborative teams approach, yet able to work independently when needed. Communicates effectively at all levels with clients and colleagues alike and thrives on responsibility and challenges.

EXPERIENCE

2018 - Current TUSK CREATIVE STUDIOS

Founder

Tusk Designs is a Long Beach digital agency focused on scaling businesses digital presence to enable them to reach their full online potential. We offer website development, branding, ux/ui, drone photography, digital marketing services.

2020 - Current

UNIVERISTY OF CALFORNIA IRVINE

Teacher Assistant

Lead discussions, grade assignments, managed communication between students and teaching staff, and prepared course material for the following classes:

- UX/UI Course
- Digital Marketing Course

2018 - 2019

SELDAT DISTRIBUTION. INC. & BLU LOGISTICS

USA Product Marketing Strategist

Marketing and development strategist collaborating with cross functional, international teams to bring a profitable portfolio of 3PL products and services to market on time and on budget that address customer needs and evolving industry dynamics.

- Collaborated with the Blu's global marketing and sales teams in LATAM to make informed marketing decisions that would benefit the wider company and optimize resources.
- Supported the sales team including the following activities but not limited too: SalesForce, lead research, go-to-market collateral, sales material, and competitive intelligence information to drive demand and enable sales team initiatives.
- Strategically developed digital marketing strategies that align with the wider Blu organizations goals and future outlook via website, email marketing, social media and SEO.
- Research and development of new customer on-boarding process (utilizing HTML, CSS JavaScript, Node.js).

Product Marketing Strategist

- Accountable for marketing activities covering warehousing, distribution, fulfilment, transportation, cold chain logistics, last mile delivery, staffing (recruitment process outsourcing), customs brokerage, and international freight forwarding
- Strategized and developed email campaigns
- Develop go-to-market collateral, sales material, and competitive intelligence information to drive demand and improve sales team initiatives
- Launch new websites and redesign legacy sites to build the ongoing relationship with customers and prospects

2016 - 2018

OCEANSTAR, INC. (MERGED W/ SELDAT DISTRIBUTION, INC. 2018)

Marketing and Sales Strategist

Developed and improved marketing initiatives to increase top funnel leads. Designed brochures, presentations, and maintained company website. Led the digital marketing initiative that help establish them with a strong online presence.

- Developed an online marketing communication strategy via website, email marketing, social media and SEO
- Collaborated with senior leadership to structure and streamline the sales process

Long Beach, CA USA

T: 714 402 9084

E: hello@austinsimpkins.com

W: austinsimpkins.com

EDUCATION

BS. BUSINESS MARKETING

California State University of Long Beach

UX/UI BOOTCAMP

University of California Irvine

SKILLS

UX / UI Design

Adobe Creative Cloud

Wordpress

Salesforce Marketing Cloud

Email Marketing

Google Marketing Suite

Print Design

HTML / CSS / JS

CERTIFICATIONS





